export const SCULPTUREA2019 = [

{
id: "question1",
question:  "1. Identify the most suitable method of reproducing same forms.",
A: "Modelling",
B: "Carving",
C: "Casting",
D: "Assemblage",
answer: "C. Casting",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question2",
question:  "2. Choose a soft wood from the options.",
A: "Ebony",
B: "Teak",
C: "Rosewood",
D: "Redwood",
answer: "D. Redwood",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question3",
question:  "3. Which of the following explains a maquette?",
A: "A preparatory drawing of an idea",
B: "A large model of a proposed project",
C: "A small clay figure of an idea",
D: "A cast figure of a hero",
answer: "C. A small clay figure of an idea",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question4",
question:  "4. Select a suitable tool for marking points for screws in assemblage of wood.",
A: "Chisel",
B: "Riffler",
C: "Bradawl",
D: "Scraper",
answer: "C. Bradawl",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question5",
question:  "5. In metal casting, the sprue serves as a",
A: "conduit.",
B: "vent.",
C: "runner.",
D: "core,",
answer: "A. conduit.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question6",
question:  "6. The grain of ebony is described as",
A: "wavy.",
B: "dense.",
C: "fibrous.",
D: "crossed.",
answer: "B. dense.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question7",
question:  "7. Choose a method of joining leather-hard clay pieces.",
A: "Pressing",
B: "Filling",
C: "Luting",
D: "Gluing",
answer: "C. Luting",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question8",
question:  "8. At what stage should a plaster mould be sized?",
A: "Dry",
B: "Moist",
C: "Wet",
D: "Hot",
answer: "A. Dry",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question9",
question:  "9. Identify a characteristic of a cured plaster.",
A: "Turns putty",
B: "Begins to set faster",
C: "Heats up to become hard",
D: "Total dryness",
answer: "D. Total dryness",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question10",
question:  "10. Select a multifunctional tool among the options.",
A: "Vice",
B: "Pincers",
C: "Calipers",
D: "Plane",
answer: "A. Vice",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question11",
question:  "11. Adding glue to papier maché renders it",
A: "smooth and strong.",
B: "slippery and shiny.",
C: "porous and waterproof.",
D: "permanent and strong.",
answer: "D. permanent and strong.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question12",
question:  "12. Firing temperature in a kiln is monitored by the use of a",
A: "thermometer.",
B: "hydrometer.",
C: "monometer.",
D: "pyrometer.",
answer: "D. pyrometer.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question13",
question:  "13. A turntable is usually useful for",
A: "modelling.",
B: "carving.",
C: "casting.",
D: "assemblage.",
answer: "A. Modelling.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question14",
question:  "14. Strops are useful for",
A: "removing Clog on oil stones.",
B: "ensuring finest cutting edge of tools.",
C: "strengthening the edge of tools.",
D: "repairing abraded oil stones.",
answer: "B. ensuring finest cutting edge of tools.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question15",
question:  "15. Which of the following is required for mounting a portrait bust?",
A: "Turntable",
B: "Bust peg",
C: "Modelling stand",
D: "Pedestal",
answer: "D. Pedestal",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question16",
question:  "16. The reason for sizing a mould is to",
A: "receive the cast.",
B: "facilitate separation.",
C: "harden the mould.",
D: "make the cast waterproof.",
answer: "B. facilitate separation.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question17",
question:  "17. Identify a finishing technique from the options.",
A: "Blocking",
B: "Luting",
C: "Soldering",
D: "Polishing",
answer: "D. Polishing",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question18",
question:  "18. Select the process of designing wood with hot metals.",
A: "Encoustic",
B: "Lithography",
C: "Pyrography",
D: "Soldering",
answer: "C. Pyrography",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question19",
question:  "19. The focus of three dimensional art is mainly on",
A: "texture and colour.",
B: "colour and space.",
C: "space and mass.",
D: "mass and texture.",
answer: "C. space and mass.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question20",
question:  "20. Which tool is required to mix concrete?",
A: "Float",
B: "Scraper",
C: "Riffler",
D: "Trowel",
answer: "D. Trowel",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question21",
question:  "21. Modelling in wax involves",
A: "splitting",
B: "wedging",
C: "kneading.",
D: "scoring.",
answer: "C. kneading.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question22",
question:  "22. A chisel stuck into woodcarving is removed by",
A: "wiggling it out.",
B: "pulling it out straight.",
C: "pouring oil around the base.",
D: "hitting the head with mallet.",
answer: "A. wiggling it out.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question23",
question:  "23. Exhibition is one of the major means of",
A: "showing the sculptor’s skills in handling tools and materials.",
B: "bringing friends and relations together for fun fair.",
C: "showing and selling sculptures.",
D: "bringing all sculptors together.",
answer: "C. showing and selling sculptures.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question24",
question:  "24. The suitable bonding technique for an assemblage of bones and shells is",
A: "nailing.",
B: "soldering.",
C: "riveting.",
D: "gluing.",
answer: "D. gluing.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question25",
question:  "25. Identify a tool for stone-carving.",
A: "Claw",
B: "Vernier",
C: "Spatula",
D: "Snips",
answer: "A. Claw",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question26",
question:  "26. Which of the following wood species is suitable for carving with a knife?",
A: "Sapele",
B: "Teak",
C: "Sese",
D: "Ebony",
answer: "C. Sese",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question27",
question:  "27. The style of Vincent Kofi’s carving is best described as",
A: "cubistic.",
B: "surrealistic.",
C: "impressionistic.",
D: "realistic.",
answer: "D. realistic.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question28",
question:  "28. Which of these is a medium for an additive sculpture?",
A: "Bronze",
B: "Plasticine",
C: "Wood",
D: "Stone",
answer: "B. Plasticine",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question29",
question:  "29. Which of the follwing is a strategy for effective marketing?",
A: "Planning",
B: "Pricing",
C: "Packaging",
D: "Designing",
answer: "A. Planning",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question30",
question:  "30. The Romans developed great taste for the sculptures of the",
A: "ancient Egyptians.",
B: "ancient Greeks.",
C: "Renaissance period.",
D: "Gothic period.",
answer: "B. ancient Greeks.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question31",
question:  "31. Terra Cotta work is modelled with",
A: "pop and sand.",
B: "cement and aggregates.",
C: "clay and sand.",
D: "slip and sawdust.",
answer: "C. clay and sand.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question32",
question:  "32. Dead plaster is caused by a prolonged exposure to",
A: "moisture.",
B: "sunlight.",
C: "heat.",
D: "air.",
answer: "A. moisture.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question33",
question:  "33. What role does metal pins play in casting?",
A: "Hold core in position",
B: "Promote flowing of molten metal",
C: "Serves as conduits",
D: "Accelerate melting of wax",
answer: "A. Hold core in position",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question34",
question:  "34. The best stage for scooping a clay sculpture is when it is",
A: "bone-dry.",
B: "leatherhard.",
C: "plastic.",
D: "soggy.",
answer: "B. leatherhard.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question35",
question:  "35. The last process in metal casting ts",
A: "chasing.",
B: "de-waxing.",
C: "pouring.",
D: "patination.",
answer: "D. patination.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question36",
question:  "36. Which of these materials is the easiest to carve?",
A: "Wood",
B: "Styrofoam",
C: "Soapstone",
D: "Plaster",
answer: "B. Styrofoam",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question37",
question:  "37. A heat-proof receptacle in which a metal is melted is known as",
A: "iron pot.",
B: "earthenware pot.",
C: "vase.",
D: "crucible.",
answer: "D. crucible.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question38",
question:  "38. Murals in sculpture usually take the form of",
A: "in-the-round.",
B: "relief.",
C: "assemblage.",
D: "construction.",
answer: "B. relief.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question39",
question:  "39. Identify the group of materials that are incompatible.",
A: "Clay and plaster",
B: "Plaster and sand",
C: "Sand and clay",
D: "Cement and plaster",
answer: "B. Plaster and sand",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question40",
question:  "40. Which of these materials is very sensitive to dampness?",
A: "Clay",
B: "Wood",
C: "PoP",
D: "Grog",
answer: "C. PoP",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},


]